We're going to share a lot of secrets today, you and I,
اليوم سوف أقوم بمشاركة العديد من الأسرار معكم.
and in doing so, I hope that we can lift
وللقيام بذلك، أرجو التخلص
some of the shame many of us feel about sex.
من بعض الخجل الذي نشعر به أثناء حديثنا عن الجنس.
How many here have ever been catcalled by a stranger?
كم عدد الناس هنا الذين تعرضوا للتحرش اللفظي من قبل شخص غريب؟
Lots of women.
الكثير من النساء.
For me, the time I remember best
بالنسبة لي، آخر مرة أتذكرها جيداً
is when that stranger was a student of mine.
عندما كان ذلك الشخص الغريب تلميذاً لدي.
He came up to me after class that night
اتجه نحوي تلك الليلة بعد انتهاء الدرس
and his words confirmed what I already knew:
وكلماته أكدت لي ما كنت على علم به:
"I am so sorry, professor.
"أنا آسف يا أستاذة.
If I had known it was you, I would never have said those things."
لو كنت أعلم أنه أنت لما تفوهت بتلك الأشياء."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I wasn't a person to him until I was his professor.
أنا لم أكن شخصاً بالنسبة له حتى أصبحت أستاذته.
This concept, called objectification,
هذا المفهوم الذي يسمى التجسيد المادي،
is the foundation of sexism,
هو أساس التمييز على أساس نوع الجنس،
and we see it reinforced through every aspect of our lives.
ونرى هذه الظاهرة تزداد على مستوى جميع جوانب حياتنا.
We see it in the government
نرى ذلك في الحكومة
that refuses to punish men
التي ترفض مُعاقبة الرجال
for raping women.
المغتصبين للنساء.
We see it in advertisements.
نرى ذلك في الإعلانات.
How many of you have seen an advertisement
كم منكم شاهد إعلاناً
that uses a woman's breast to sell an entirely unrelated product?
حيث يُستخدم ثدي المرأة لبيع بضاعة ليس لها علاقة بذلك؟
Or movie after movie after movie
أو فِلماً تلو الآخر
that portrays women as only love interests?
تُجسد فيه المرأة كعشيقة فقط؟
These examples might seem inconsequential and harmless,
هذه الأمثلة قد تبدو غير منطقية وغير ضارة،
but they're insidious,
لكنها ماكرة،
slowly building into a culture that refuses to see women as people.
لأنها تنشر ثقافة ترفض مُعاملة المرأة كإنسان.
We see this in the school that sends home a 10-year-old girl
نرى ذلك في المدرسة التي تُرسل طفلة في العاشرة من عمرها إلى بيتها
because her clothes were a distraction to boys trying to learn,
لأن ملابسها ملفتة للأولاد الذين يحاولون التعلم،
or the government that refuses to punish men for raping women
أو في الحكومة التي ترفض معاقبة الرجال المغتصبين للنساء
over and over,
المزيد والمزيد،
or the woman who is killed
أو المرأة التي تم قتلها
because she asked a man to stop grinding on her on the dance floor.
لأنها طلبت من الرجل أن يتوقف عن الاصطدام بها على ساحة الرقص.
Media plays a large role in perpetuating the objectification of women.
تلعب وسائل الإعلام دوراً كبيراً في جعل المرأة مجرد شيء مادي.
Let's consider the classic romantic comedy.
بالنسبة للأفلام الرومانسية الكوميدية التقليدية مثلا.
We're typically introduced to two kinds of women in these movies,
في الغالب تُعرض نوعين من النساء في هذا النوع من الأفلام،
two kinds of desirable women, anyway.
نوعين من النساء المرغوبات، على كل حال.
The first is the sexy bombshell.
الأولى هي المرأة المثيرة والجذابة.
This is the unbelievably gorgeous woman with the perfect body.
هذه المرأة الجميلة بشكل لا يصدق مع جسد مثالي.
Our leading man has no trouble identifying her
الرجل في دور البطولة ليس لديه أي عقبات في التعرف عليها
and even less trouble having sex with her.
ولا حتى عقبات من أجل ممارسة الجنس معها.
The second is our leading lady,
الثانية هي المرأة في دور البطولة،
the beautiful but demure woman our leading man falls in love with
جميلة لكن رزينة، يقع في حبها الرجل البطل
despite not noticing her at first
بالرغم من عدم ملاحظتها في أول الأمر
or not liking her if he did.
أو عدم الإعجاب بها حتى لو لاحظها.
The first is the slut.
الأولى وقحة وقذرة.
She is to be consumed and forgotten.
يتم استغلالها ومن ثم نسيانها.
She is much too available.
وهي متاحة بشكل كبير.
The second is desirable but modest,
الثانية مرغوب فيها ولكنها محتشمة،
and therefore worthy of our leading man's future babies.
لذلك فهي تستحق أن تكون أماً لأطفال رجلنا البطل في المستقبل.
Marriage material.
صالحة للزواج.
We're actually told that women have two roles,
يُقال لنا بأنه يوجد دورين للمرأة،
but these two roles have a difficult time existing within the same woman.
لكن من الصعب إيجاد هذين الدورين في نفس المرأة.
On the rare occasion that I share with a new acquaintance
ففي المناسبات النادرة التي أشارك فيها أحد معارفي الجدد
that I study sex,
حول دراستي للجنس،
if they don't end the conversation right then,
إن لم ينهوا المحادثة وقتئذٍ،
they're usually pretty intrigued.
سوف يكونون مفتونين عادة.
"Oh. Tell me more."
" أوه! أخبرنى بالمزيد."
So I do.
لذا أقوم بذلك.
"I'm really interested in studying the sexual behaviors
"أنا في الحقيقة مهتمة بدراسة التصرفات الجنسية
of pregnant and postpartum couples."
للزوجين في فترة الحمل وما بعدها."
At this point I get a different kind of response.
عند هذه النقطة لاحظت نوعاَ مختلفاَ من الإجابات.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Oh. Huh.
"اوه! هاه.
Do pregnant people even have sex?
هل المرأة الحامل تمارس الجنس؟
Have you thought about studying sexual desire
هل فكرت في دراسة الرغبة الجنسية
or orgasms?
أو الذروة الجنسية؟
That would be interesting, and sexy."
قد يبدو ذلك مثيراَ وشيقاَ."
Tell me. What are the first words that come to mind
أخبرني عن الكلمات الأولى التي تخطر في بالك
when you picture a pregnant woman?
عندما تتخيل امرأة حامل؟
I asked this question in a survey of over 500 adults,
لقد قمت بسؤال 500 شخص بالغ هذا السؤال عند القيام باستطلاع،
and most responded with "belly" or "round"
المعظم أجابوا بكلمة "بطن" أو "مستديرة"
and "cute."
و"لطيفة."
This didn't surprise me too much.
هذا لم يفاجئني كثيراَ.
What else do we label as cute?
ماذا نصف أيضاَ باللطيف؟
Babies. Puppies. Kittens.
الأطفال والجراء والقطط.
The elderly. Right?
كبار السن. أليس كذلك؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
When we label an adult as cute, though,
عندما نصف الشخص البالغ باللطيف
we take away a lot of their intelligence,
فإننا نُقلّل من ذكائه،
their complexity.
وشخصياتهم المركّبة.
We reduce them to childlike qualities.
نُشبّههم بالصفات الطفولية.
I also asked heterosexual men
كما طلبت من رجال سويّين جنسياً
to imagine a woman that they're partnered with is pregnant,
آن يتخيلوا مواعدة امرأه حامل،
and then asked women to imagine that they are pregnant,
ثم طلبنا من نساء أن يتيخلن أنفسهن حوامل،
and then tell me the first words that come to mind
ثم يخبروني بالكلمات الأولى التي تطرأ على مخيلتهم
when they imagine having sex.
عند تخيلهم مُمارسة الجنس.
Most of the responses were negative.
كانت معظم الإجابات سلبية.
"Gross."
"مُقزّز"
"Awkward."
"مُحرج"
"Not sexy." "Odd."
"غير مثير." "غريب."
"Uncomfortable."
"غير مُريح."
"How?"
"كيف؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Not worth the trouble." "Not worth the risk."
"لا يستحق العناء." "لا يستحق المخاطرة."
That last one really stuck with me.
الأمر الأخير علق في مخيلتي.
We might think that because we divorce pregnant women and moms from sexuality,
قد يتبادر ذلك إلى أذهاننا بما أننا نُقصي النساء الحوامل والأمهات من الجنس،
we are removing the constraints of sexual objectification.
فإننا نتخلص من العقبات المتعلقة بالتجسيد الموضوعي للجنس.
They experience less sexism. Right?
هم يتعرضون لتمييزعلى أساس الجنس أقلّ. صحيح؟
Not exactly.
ليس تماماً.
What happens instead is a different kind of objectification.
ما يحدث عوض عن ذلك هو نوع آخر من التجسيد الموضوعي.
In my efforts to explain this to others,
بمحاولاتي لتفسير ذلك للآخرين،
one conversation led to the Venus of Willendorf,
أدّت مُحادثة واحدة إلى فينوس ويلندورف،
a Paleolithic figurine scholars assumed was a goddess of love and beauty,
وهي آلهة الحب والجمال كما افترض علماء العصر الحجري القديم،
hence the name Venus.
بالتالي اسمها فينوس.
This theory was later revised, though,
وقد نُقّحت هذه النظرية في وقت لاحق،
when scholars noted the sculptor's obvious focus
عندما لاحظ العلماء أن النحات ركّز بشكل واضح
on the figurine's reproductive features:
على تمثيل الملامح التناسلية:
large breasts, considered ideal for nursing;
أثداء كبيرة، مثاليّة للترضيع؛
a round, possibly pregnant belly;
بطن مستدير، ربما حامل؛
the remnants of red dye, alluding to menstruation or birth.
بقايا صبغ أحمر، تُشير إلى الحيض أو الولادة.
They also assumed that she was meant to be held or placed lying down
كما أنهم افترضوا أنها من المقرر أن تكون في وضع استلقاء
because her tiny feet don't allow her to be freestanding.
لأن ساقيها الصغيرتين لا تسمح لها بالوقوف.
She also had no face.
كما لا يوجد لديها وجه.
For this reason, it was assumed that she was a representation of fertility
لهذا السبب، كان من المفترض أن تُمثّل الخصوبة
and not a portrait of a person.
وليس صورة لشخص.
She was an object.
كانت غرضاً.
In the history of her interpretation,
في تاريخ تفسيرها،
she went from object of ideal beauty and love
تحولت من غرض يرمز إلى الجمال والحب
to object of reproduction.
إلى غرض للتكاثر.
I think this transition speaks more
أعتقد أن هذا التحول يدلّ أكثر
about the scholars who have interpreted her purpose
على العلماء الذين حددوا الغرض منها
than the actual purpose of the figurine herself.
عوضاَ عن الغرض الأساسي وهو معرفة نفسها.
When a woman becomes pregnant,
حينما تصبح المرأة حاملاً
she leaves the realm of men's sexual desire
تترك المملكة الخاصة برغبة الرجل الجنسية
and slides into her reproductive and child-rearing role.
وتتجه إلى العملية التناسلية وطرق تربية الأطفال.
In doing so, she also becomes
وأيضا تصبح
the property of the community,
ملكية خاصة للمجتمع،
considered very important but only because she's pregnant. Right?
يهتمون بها فقط لأنها حامل. صحيح؟
I've taken to calling this the Willendorf effect,
وأطلقت على هذا تأثير الويلندورف
and once again we see it reinforced in many aspects of her life.
مرة أخرى نراها محفزة في الكثير من جوانب حياتها
Has anyone here ever been visibly pregnant?
من منكم سبق له الحمل؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Yeah. Lots of you, right?
الكثير منكم، صحيح؟
So how many of you ever had a stranger touch your belly during pregnancy,
كم منكم لمس بطنها شخص غريب في فترة حملها
maybe without even asking your permission first?
ربما من دون أن يستأذن؟
Or told what you can and cannot eat
أو قيل لها ماذا يجب أن تأكل أو لا تأكل
by somebody who is not your doctor, your medical care provider?
من شخص ليس طبيبك أو مقدم الرعاية الطبية
Or asked private questions about your birth plan?
أو أن تُسأل أسئلة خاصة عن طريقة ولادتك؟
And then told why those choices are all wrong?
وإخبارك أن جميع هذه الإختيارت خاطئة
Yeah, me too.
نعم حتى أنا
Or had a server refuse to bring you a glass of wine?
أو أن يتم رفض تقديم النبيذ لها.
This one might give you pause, I know, but stay with me.
قد يدهشكم هذا أعلم بذلك، لكن انتظروا
This is a huge secret.
هذا سر كبير
It is actually safe to drink in moderation during pregnancy.
في الواقع إنه من الآمن شرب النبيذ باعتدال أثناء الحمل.
Many of us don't know this
العديد منا لا يعلمون بذلك
because doctors don't trust pregnant women with this secret --
لأن الأطباء لا يثقون في المرأة الحامل
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
especially if she's less educated or a woman of color.
خصوصاَ غير المثقفة وذوات البشرة السمراء
What this tells us is,
ماذا نستنتج من هذا
this Willendorf effect, it's also classist and racist.
هذا تأثير ويلندروف، وهو عنصري و مُفرق.
It's present when the government reminds women
في الحاضر حينما ذكرت الحكومة
with every new anti-choice bill
منع الإجهاض
that the contents of her uterus are not her own,
ذلك أن الرحم ليس ملكاَ لها
or when an ob-gyn says,
أو عندما تخبرها طبيبتها
"While it's safe to have sex during pregnancy,
بينما هو آمن أن تمارس الجنس أثناء الحمل
sometimes you never know.
أحيانا لا تعلم ذلك.
Better safe than sorry, right?"
السلامة و لا الندم، صحيح
She's denied basic privacy and bodily autonomy
لا تتقبل خصوصيتها ولا استقلالية جسدها
under the guise of "be a good mother."
إتباعاَ لمقولة سأكون أماً جيدة
We don't trust her to make her own decisions.
نحن لا نثق بها و بقراراتها.
She's cute, remember?
إنها لطيفة، أتذكرون؟
When we tell women
عندما نخبر المرأة
that sexual pleasure -- excuse me.
أن الرغبة الجنسية، عفوا
When we tell women that sex isn't worth the risk during pregnancy,
أقصد عندما نخبرها أن الجنس لا يستحق المخاطرة أثناء الحمل
what we're telling her is that her sexual pleasure doesn't matter.
ما نخبرها به أن رغبتها الجنسية ليست مهمة.
So what we are telling her is that she in fact doesn't matter,
في الواقع نحن نقول لها أنك لست مهمة بالنسبة لنا
even though the needs of her fetus are not at odds with her own needs.
حتى ما يحتاجه جنينها ليس ضمن احتياجاتها.
So medical providers,
لذلك الأطباء
such as the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists
مثل كلية النساء والولادة الأمريكية
have the opportunity to educate about the safety of sex during pregnancy.
تقوم بتثقيف عن كيفية ممارسة الجنس الآمن للمرأة الحامل.
So what do the experts say?
إذاً ماذا يقول الأطباء؟
ACOG actually has no public official statement
المنظمة الأمريكية للنساء والولادة ليس لديها رأي مثبت
about the safety of sex during pregnancy.
حول ممارسة الجنس الآمن للمرأة الحامل
Guidance from the Mayo Clinic is generally positive
عيادات مايو (مؤسسة طبية غير ربحية) ترى أنه من الآمن
but presented with a caveat:
مقدمة مذكرة قانونية بذلك
"Although most women can safely have sex throughout pregnancy,
"أن المرأة الحامل بإمكانها ممارسة الجنس
sometimes it's best to be cautious."
ولكن أحياناً يجب الحذر."
Some women don't want to have sex during pregnancy,
بعض الحوامل لا يرغبن بممارسة الجنس
and that's OK.
وذلك مقبول.
Some women do want to have sex during pregnancy,
والبعض الآخر يرغبن بممارسة الجنس
and that's OK, too.
وهو أيضا مقبول.
What needs to stop is society telling women
ما يجب أن يتوقف هو ما يقوله المجتمع للنساء
what they can and cannot do with their bodies.
ماذا يجب أن يفعلوا وما لا يجب أن يفعلوا بأجسادهن
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Pregnant women are not faceless, identity-less vessels of reproduction
فالمرأة الحامل ليست شخصا مجهول أو بلا هوية، مجرد وعاء
who can't stand on their own two feet.
لا يستطيع الوقوف على قدميه.
But the truth is, the real secret is,
لكن الواقع هو السر الحقيقي
we tell all women that their sexual pleasure doesn't matter.
أننا نقول لها أن رغبتها الجنسية لا تهم.
We refuse to even acknowledge that women who have sex with women
إننا نرفض فكرة وجود امرأة تمارس الجنس مع امرأة
or women who don't want children even exist.
أو امرأة ليس لديها رغبة في الإنجاب.
"Oh, it's just a phase ...
"أوه، إنها مجرد مرحلة...
she just needs the right man to come along."
إنها فقط تنتظر الرجل المناسب أن يأتي."
Every time a woman has sex
في كل مرة تمارس فيها المرأة الجنس
simply because it feels good,
ببساطة لأنه يشعرها بالسعادة
it is revolutionary.
إنها ثورة.
She is revolutionary.
إنها ثورية.
She is pushing back against society's insistence
إنها تدافع ضد إصرار المجتمع
that she exist simply for men's pleasure
على أنها موجودة لرغبة الرجل
or for reproduction.
أو للتكاثر.
A woman who prioritizes her sexual needs is scary,
المرأة التي يكون احتياجها الجنسي أولويتها مخيفة
because a woman who prioritizes her sexual needs prioritizes herself.
ذلك لأنها تقدم احتياجها الجنسي على نفسها.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
That is a woman demanding that she be treated as an equal.
ذلك لأن المرأة تحاول جاهدة أن تُعامل بمساواة.
That is a woman who insists
لذلك المرأة تصر
that you make room for her at the table of power,
أن يكون لها صوت
and that is the most terrifying of all
وهذا مخيف للجميع
because we can't make room for her
لأننا لا نستطيع إعطائها صوت
without some of us giving up the extra space we hold.
من دون وجود بعضنا يتنازل.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I have one last secret for you.
لدي سر أخير لكم
I am the mother of two boys
أنا أم لطفلين
and we could use your help.
وبإمكاننا استخدام مساعدتكم
Even though my boys hear me say regularly
حتى أبنائي يسمعونني أقول عادة
that it's important for men to recognize women as equals
أن على الرجال معاملة المرأة بمساواة
and they see their father modeling this,
وهم يرون أبيهم يفعل ذلك
we need what happens in the world to reinforce what happens in our home.
ما نريده أن يحدث في العالم هو أن نعزّز ما يحدث في منازلنا
This is not a men's problem or a women's problem.
وهي ليست مشكلة خاصة بالرجال أو النساء
This is everyone's problem,
هذه مشكلة الجميع.
and we all play a role in dismantling systems of inequality.
جميعنا نلعب دوراً في ترك عادات عدم المساواة
For starters, we have got to stop telling women
بدايةَ يجب علينا عدم إخبار النساء
what they can and cannot do with their bodies.
ماذا يجب أن يفعلن وما لا يجب أن يفعلن بأجسادهن.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
This includes not treating pregnant women like community property.
هذا يدخل ضمن عدم معاملة المرأة كملكية خاصة للمجتمع.
If you don't know her, don't even ask to touch her belly.
إذا كنت لا تعرفها، لا تتجرأ على لمس بطنها.
You wouldn't anybody else.
لن تكون شخصا آخر.
Don't tell her what she can and cannot eat.
لا تقل لها ماذا تأكل.
Don't ask her private details about her medical decisions.
لا تسألها عن الأمور الخاصة بقرارتها الطبية.
This also includes understanding
وأيضا التفهم
that even if you are personally against abortion,
حتى لو كنت ضد الإجهاض شخصياً،
you can still fight for a woman's right to choose.
بإمكانك مواصلة الدفاع عن حق المرأة في الإختيار
When it comes to women's equality, the two need not oppose one another.
حينما يكون الموضوع عن مساواة المرأة الاثنين لا يتعارضون
If you're somebody who has sex with women,
إذا كنت قد حضيت بممارسة الجنس مع امرأة
prioritize her pleasure.
فالأولوية لرغبتها الجنسية.
If you don't know how, ask.
إذا كنت لا تعلم، اسألها.
If you have children --
إذا كان لديها أطفال ...
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
have conversations about sex as early as possible,
أتحدث عن الجنس مبكرا قدر الإمكان
because kids don't look up s-e-x in the dictionary anymore.
لأن الأطفال لا يبحثون عنه في القاموس.
They look it up on the internet.
بل على الإنترنت.
And when you're having those conversations about sex,
عندما تتحدثون عن الجنس
don't center them on reproduction only.
لا تركزوا على التكاثر فقط.
People have sex for many reasons,
هناك أسباب كثير لممارسة الجنس
some because they want a baby,
البعض يريدون طفل،
but most of us have sex because it feels good.
لكن الكثير منا يمارسونه لأنه يشعرهم بالسعادة.
Admit it.
اعترف بذلك.
And regardless of whether you have children or not,
بغض النظر لديك أطفال أو ليس لديك
support comprehensive sex education that doesn't shame our teenagers.
دعم التثقيف والاطلاع على الثقافة الجنسية ليس محرجا للمراهقين
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Nothing positive comes from shaming teens
لا يوجد شي إيجابي يأتي من إحراجهم
for their sexual desires, behaviors,
لرغباتهم الجنسية و تصرفاتهم
other than positive STD and pregnancy tests.
بغض النظر عن الأمراض الجنسية وتحاليل الحمل الإيجابية.
Every single day, we are all given the opportunity
في كل يوم هناك فرصة
to disrupt patterns of inequality.
للتخلص من عادات عدم المساواة.
I think we can all agree that it's worth the trouble to do so.
أعتقد جميعنا نتفق أن الموضوع يستحق العناء.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)